JULIUS WINSTON AMOATWO

Accra + 233

Tel: 055-296-5559

Email: juliuswinston7@gmail.com

Summary

Professional and well-grounded Bachelor of Science Computer Science graduate with adaptability and an unquenchable thirst for acquiring new knowledge and expertise. Energetic individual with outstanding interpersonal, analytical and critical thinking skills. Poised to build valuable experience and ready to contribute to team success in any way possible.

Skills

- Web App Development
 - ✓ Html
 - ✓ CSS
 - ✓ JavaScript
 - ✓ PHP
 - ✓ Laravel
 - ✓ Codeigniter
 - ✓ Wordpress
 - ✓ MySql
- Mobile App Development
 - ✓ Flutter
- Java programming
- Python programming

- Arduino programming
- Project management
- Team collaboration
- Documentation
- Leadership
- Utility Software Installation
- Operating Systems Installation
- Hardware Installation
- Adobe Illustrator
- Adobe Photoshop
- Customer service
- Data management
- Data entry
- SEO Techniques

Experience

TANK/LINE INTEGRITY TEST TECHNICIAN | 07/2021 to Present

UNIVERSAL ENGINEERING AND CONSULTANCY SERVICES LIMITED – Accra

- Test product tanks (fuel tanks) for significant product leaks.
- Test product dispensers for significant product leaks.
- Test product lines for significant product leaks.
- Interacting with OMCs, site managers, site owners, and various site workers to ensure smooth operations.
- Using the Leighton O'Brien Field Software to perform tank/line tests.
- Educating various site stakeholders on safety practices through a toolbox meeting.
- Generate official billable reports on work done on various sites.
- Using the Tank and Line Reporting (TLR) and Tank Test Analysis (TTA) systems (software) to generate and report on test results

FULLSTACK DEVELOPER | 05/2021 to 07/2021

ORION TTI - Accra

- Website and software application designing, building, update, and maintenance.
- Using scripting or authoring languages, management tools, content creation tools, applications, and digital media.
- Conferring with teams to resolve conflicts, prioritize needs, develop content criteria, or choose solutions.
- Developing or validating test routines and schedules to ensure that test cases mimic external interfaces and address all browser and device types.
- Editing, writing, or designing Website content, and directing team members who produce content.
- Maintaining an understanding of the latest Web applications and programming practices through education, study, and participation in conferences, workshops, and groups.
- Identifying problems uncovered by customer feedback and testing, and correcting or referring problems to appropriate personnel for correction.
- Evaluating code to ensure it meets industry standards, is valid, is properly structured, and is compatible with browsers, devices, or operating systems.
- Identifying user needs by analyzing technical requirements.

WEB DEVELOPER / IT TECHNICIAN | 01/2021 to 04/2021

Gigs Incorporation Limited – Accra

- Website and software application designing, building, update, and maintenance.
- Facilitating web development classes.
- Using scripting or authoring languages, management tools, content creation tools, applications, and digital media.
- Conferring with teams to resolve conflicts, prioritize needs, develop content criteria, or choose solutions.
- Developing or validating test routines and schedules to ensure that test cases mimic external interfaces and address all browser and device types.
- Editing, writing, or designing Website content, and directing team members who produce content.
- Maintaining an understanding of the latest Web applications and programming practices through education, study, and participation in conferences, workshops, and groups.
- Back up files from Web sites to local directories for recovery.
- Identifying problems uncovered by customer feedback and testing, and correcting or referring problems to appropriate personnel for correction.
- Evaluating code to ensure it meets industry standards, is valid, is properly structured, and is compatible with browsers, devices, or operating systems.
- Identifying user needs by analyzing technical requirements.

FULLSTACK DEVELOPER | 09/2020 to 01/2021

Sharks Hive – Accra

- Collaborate with support team to assist client stakeholders with emergent technical issues and develop effective solutions.
- Develop product and technology roadmap and strategy from concept to launch.
- Access code during testing stage to determine potential glitches and bugs.
- Direct all software design, architecture, and programming.
- Review project requirements to identify customer expectations and number of resources to meet goals.
- Resolve customer issues by establishing workarounds and solutions and by debugging and creating defect fixes.
- Establish and maintain key relationships with business stakeholders to promote future opportunity.

FULLSTACK DEVELOPER / IT SUPPORT | 09/2019 to 09/2020

Accra Digital Center - Accra

Fullstack Developer Duties:

- Collaborate with support team to assist client stakeholders with emergent technical issues and develop effective solutions.
- Develop product and technology roadmap and strategy from concept to launch.
- Access code during testing stage to determine potential glitches and bugs.
- Direct all software design, architecture and programming.
- Review project requirements to identify customer expectations and number of resources to meet goals.
- Resolve customer issues by establishing workarounds and solutions and by debugging and creating defect fixes.
- Establish and maintain key relationships with business stakeholders to promote future opportunity.

IT Support Duties:

- Installing and configuring computer hardware, software, systems, networks, printers, and scanners
- Monitoring and maintaining computer systems and networks
- Responding in a timely manner to service issues and requests
- Providing technical support across the company (this may be in person or over the phone)
- Setting up accounts for new users
- Repairing and replacing equipment as necessary
- Testing new technology

INTERN | 06/2015 to 10/2015

United States Agency for International Development (USAID), West Africa – Ghana, Accra

- Coordinated with management and supervisors and welcomed constructive criticism for areas needing improvement.
- Administered digital filing systems, keeping records well-organized and easily retrievable by team members.
- Data entry with google sheets.
- Data entry with an accounting system (cannot disclose name of system due to a NDA).
- Maintained strict security protocols to protect confidentiality of all data.
- Kept office equipment functioning optimally by troubleshooting problems and completing basic maintenance.
- Assisted other team members to create new user accounts on system and educated them on how to be security conscious and keep their personal accounts safe and secure.

MOBILE BANKER | 2013

Prostaff Limited Accra – Ghana

- Deposit checks for customers
- Pay bills for customers
- Transfer funds
- View customer balance information
- Customer service
- Customer care

Education and Training

University of Energy and Natural Resources – Sunyani | Bachelor of Science

Computer Science 2015/2019

Live Projects

https://phoenixincorporation.com/

https://primaduediligenceconsult.com/

https://sikadanhomes.org/

https://gigsincorporation.com/

Accomplishments

- President of the Computer Science and Information Technology Students' Association | 2018/2019 academic year.
- President of Creativity Group (Kumasi Hive) Sunyani Chapter | 2017/2018 and 2018/2019 academic years.
- Student Representative Council Parliament Member | 2018/2019 academic year.
- Student Representative Council Disciplinary Committee Chairman | 2018/2019 academic year.
- Student Representative Council Privileges Committee Chairman | 2018/2019 academic year.

References

Mr. Godwin Gampson

Chief Accountant, USAID West Africa - United States of America Embassy, Accra, Ghana

Dr. Benjamin Weyori

H.O.D, Computer Science and Information Technology Department – University of Energy and Natural Resources

Mr. Bright Arhin

Head I.T Manager, Accra Digital Center